上尉，有收到玛鲁里安星系的回应吗？
Any response from the Malurians, lieutenant?
长官，从收到最初的求救呼叫之后就再没收到消息了
Nothing since their original distress call, sir.
科学考察队那边怎么样？
What about the science team?
曼维先生有一个功能强大的通讯器
Dr. Manway had a special transmitter.
长官，没有任何发现，我正在扫描所有频率
There's nothing, sir. I'm scanning all frequencies.
他们如果收到信息一定会回应的
They have to answer.
舰长
Captain.
他们或许不会回应了
They will not answer.
对这个星系的远距离扫描显示这里没有生命迹象
The long-range sensor sweep of this system reveals no sign of life.
这不可能
That can't be.
上次人口普查的报告统计
The last census reported a total inhabitation
这里居民总数超过40亿
of more than 4 billion people.
长官，我确认没有任何生命迹象
I register no life readings at all, sir.
这不可能，到底发生了什么事？
That's impossible. What could have happened?
如果发生波及整个星系的灾难，我们一定会提前知道
We would have known in advance of any system-wide catastrophe,
而且，如果发生了星际大战
and in the event of an interplanetary war,
也会有大量的放射性残留物
there would be considerable radioactive residue.
我们的仪器只检测到正常范围内的背景辐射
Our instruments show only normal background radiation.
还存在其他的可能性吗？
Any other possibilities?
长官，目前还不清楚
Unknown, sir.
如果存在任何致病生物
Sensor readings would've revealed
探测器都会检测出来，但没有任何发现
the presence of any disease organisms. They do not.
而且，我们一周前还收到这个星系的例行报告
In addition, we received a routine report from this system only a week ago.
即使是辛巴淋血烧病 也不会在那么短的时间内使那么多人死亡
Even the Symbalene blood burn does not act that swiftly.
舰长，刚开启了防护罩
Captain, shields just snapped on.
有物体在以数级曲速向我方驶来
Something heading in at multiwarp speeds.
苏鲁先生，战术规避
Evasive manoeuvres, Mr. Sulu.
舰长，那是一个威力极大的能量箭
It's an extremely powerful bolt of energy, captain.
史考特先生，护盾满功率运行
Full power to the shields, Mr. Scott.
已将可用能量转至护盾
I'm giving them all we've got.
全体人员，红色警戒
All hands, red alert.
相位炮组，随时待命
Phaser banks, stand by.
光子鱼雷，红色警戒，红色警戒
Photon torpedoes, condition red. Condition red.
即将命中星舰
It's going to hit.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilisations,
勇敢的航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：sholto
校对：Micezhang
第二季第三集
狸猫换太子
- 护盾运转正常 - 好的
- Shields still holding. - Good.
这只是暂时的，舰长
Temporarily, captain.
我们的护盾吸收了相当于
Our shields absorbed the energy
我们光子鱼雷90%的能量
equivalent to 90 of our photon torpedoes.
90%？
Ninety?
恕我直言，抵御第一次进攻
I may add, the energy used in repulsing this first attack
已经消耗了护盾20%的能量
reduced our shielding power 20 percent.
第一次进攻，长官？
First attack, sir?
上尉，我想对方还会继续进攻的
I think we can expect others, lieutenant.
我们还可以抵抗3次这样的攻击
We can resist three more such attacks.
第四次攻击将彻底撕裂护盾
The fourth will shatter our shields completely.
史波克先生，查明攻击来源
Mr. Spock, pinpoint the source.
- 苏鲁先生，战术规避 - 是的，长官
- Mr. Sulu, evasive manoeuvres. - Aye, sir.
上尉，联系星际舰队指挥部
Lieutenant, contact Starfleet Command.
把这些记录到舰长日志里，告诉他们发生了什么
Patch in my log. Tell them what has happened.
玛鲁里安星人
That the Malurian race
似乎被一个未知组织歼灭了
seems to have been destroyed by an unknown agency,
我们正遭受不明武装力量的袭击
and that we are under attack by an unidentified force.
舵手，做战术规避
Helmsman, I said evasive manoeuvres.
长官，动力不足
We're losing power, sir.
长官，我不得不把曲速引擎的能量转移到护盾
I'm having to divert the warp engine power into the shields, sir,
如果还想要保护的话
if you want the protection.
史波克先生，那些能量箭的速度是多少？
Mr. Spock, the speed of those bolts?
舰长，大约15级曲速
Approximately warp 15, captain.
我们逃脱不了，好吧，史考特，就这么干吧
Then we can't outrun them. Good, Scotty, we're doing the right thing.
史波克先生，攻击来源呢？
Source, Spock.
不明，舰长，传感器范围内没有目标
Unknown, captain. Nothing within sensor range.
发现了，舰长，很小的物体
Something now, captain. Very small.
方位123°，标记18
Bearing: 123 degrees. Marked: 18.
距离9万公里
Range: 90,000 kilometres.
苏鲁先生，那就是我们的攻击目标，准备光子鱼雷
That's our target, Mr. Sulu. Prepare photon torpedoes.
长官，护盾还在运行
Shields still holding, sir.
但是驱动引擎的能量已经下降接近临界值了
But the drain on the engines is reaching the critical point.
星舰刚失去了曲速航行的能力，转换到脉冲驱动
We just lost warp-manoeuvring power, switching to impulse.
长官，光子鱼雷已装备完成
Photon torpedoes armed, sir.
史波克先生，目标移动位置了吗？
Has the target changed location, Mr. Spock?
没有，长官，它停在原地
No, sir. Holding steady.
苏鲁先生，准备发射2号光子鱼雷
Ready photon torpedo number two, Mr. Sulu.
准备好了，长官
Ready, sir.
开火
Fire.
鱼雷已发射
Torpedo away.
正中目标
Direct hit.
攻击无效，目标吸收了鱼雷全部能量
No effect. Target absorbed full energy of our torpedo.
吸收了？
Absorbed it?
史波克先生，你的仪器一定出故障了
There must be damage to your instruments, Spock.
长官，仪器没出故障
They're in good working order, captain.
但是什么物体能吸收那么多能量而不被摧毁呢？
But what could have absorbed that much energy and survived?
- 上尉，跟对方建立通话 - 是的
- Lieutenant, try to make contact. - Aye.
长官，他们再次开火
Sir, they've fired another.
史考特先生，我们能扛过去吗？
Can we take it, Mr. Scott?
长官，有些麻烦
That's problematical, sir.
舰长，护盾失效了，我们撑不过下次攻击了
Captain, the shields are down. We cannot survive another hit.
上尉，有消息吗？
Anything, lieutenant?
长官，仍在尝试
I'm trying, sir.
打开翻译机器
Translator computer.
打开所有通信频率
All hailing frequencies open.
是，长官，所有通信频率已开启
Aye, sir. All hailing frequencies open.
致身份不明的飞船
To unidentified vessel.
我是联邦星舰进取号的舰长詹姆士·寇克
This is Captain James Kirk of the USS Enterprise.
我们在执行一项和平任务
We are on a peaceful mission.
我们对你或任何其他生命都不会造成伤害
We mean no harm to you or any life forms.
请和我们通信
Please communicate with us.
史波克先生，有什么新进展吗？
Any further readings, Mr. Spock?
舰长，我正在计算
Computing now, captain.
重量：500千克
Weight: 500 kilograms.
形状：近似圆柱体
Shape: Roughly cylindrical.
长度：超过1米
Length: A fraction over 1 meter.
500公斤重但只有1米长？
Five hundred kilos and only 1 meter long?
什么样的智慧生命会在那么小的物体里？
What kind of intelligent creatures could exist in a thing that small?
史考特先生，智慧生物不必有很大的体积
Intelligence does not necessarily require bulk, Mr. Scott.
舰长，我们从那艘飞船上获取到一条信号
Captain, we're getting a signal from the spacecraft.
- 上尉，把它播放出来 - 是，长官
- Put it on audio, lieutenant. - Yes, sir.
长官，只能把信号处理到这么清晰了
It's impossible to get it any clearer, sir.
分析部，研究这条信息，破译它
Analysis Sector, have them study and decode it.
分析部，频道1，主电脑，破译
Analysis Sector, Channel 1, main computer, decode.
舰长
Captain,
这是某种二进制的信息
this message is a sort of binary.
非常精密，极其简练
Extremely sophisticated, compressed,
同时承载几条信道的信息
carrying several channels at once.
- 你能破译它吗？ - 舰长，我还没有头绪
- Can you decode it? - No clue as yet, captain.
等一下
A moment.
传输速度逐渐下降
Transmission speed has stepped down.
更慢了
Much slower.
看起来像是一组二进制数
It seems to be a single binary.
这是数学表达式，是的，只有1个词
It's mathematical. Yes, one symbol.
是“重复”
The symbol "repeat."
长官，这不是星舰的通信编码
Sir, that isn't in the Starfleet code,
这是旧式的星际通信编码
it's an old-style interplanetary code.
真令人惊讶
Fascinating.
重复什么？我发送的信息吗？
Repeat what? The message I sent?
舰长，看起来是这样的
It would seem so, captain.
我是联邦星舰进取号的舰长詹姆士·寇克
This is Captain James Kirk of the USS Enterprise.
我们在星系的这个区域执行一项和平任务
We are on a peaceful mission in this part of the galaxy.
我们对你没有敌意
We have no hostile intentions.
我们要求识别身份
We request identity.
长官，又接收到另一条信号
It's another signal now, sir.
舰长，这次是一个公式
It's a formula, captain.
他们用数学表达式给我们传送了一条信息
They're sending us a mathematical message
并且要求语言通信
and requesting language equivalents.
他们想联系我们
They're trying to communicate.
把舰船的翻译器连接到通信频道
Tie in the ship's translator to the communication channel.
- 让他们根据自己的速度读取信息 - 是，舰长
- Let them take it at their own speed. - Aye, captain.
上尉，切断电源
Cut power, lieutenant.
因为过载烧坏了
Overloaded and burned out.
我猜他们的接收能力比我们的输送能力高
I guess they can take it faster than we can give it.
舰长，又接收到一条信息
Captain, the message is coming in now.
联邦星舰进取号，我是诺曼
USS Enterprise. This is Nomad.
我在执行一项和平任务
My mission is nonhostile.
很显然，在电脑烧坏之前他们获取了需要的信息
Apparently, they got what they needed before the computers burned out.
诺曼？
Nomad?
我请求面对面交流，你能离开你的星舰吗？
Require communication. Can you leave your ship?
因为星舰尺寸的不同，我们无法登录你的星舰
It is impossible to come aboard your ship because of the size differential.
不合逻辑的推论，你的结论和事实不一致
Non sequitur. Your facts are uncoordinated.
我们准备把你传送到我们星舰上
We are prepared to beam you aboard our ship.
这个安排很令人满意
That will be satisfactory.
你需要什么特别的环境吗？
Do you require any special conditions,
特殊的大气或环境？
any particular atmosphere or environment?
- 不需要，我会登上你的星舰 - 好的
- Negative. I will come aboard. - Good.
待在原地不要动，我们锁定了你的位置
Hold your position. We're locked onto your coordinates.
我们将把你传送到星舰上
We'll beam you aboard.
舰长，你真的要把它带到星舰上？
Captain, you're not really gonna bring it in here?
史考特，你还有其他的选择吗？
Do we have any choice, Scotty?
而且，一旦它到了船上，它就不会再攻击星舰了
Besides, once it's aboard, it won't be taking any more shots at us.
上尉，找一个机械工修理电脑
Lieutenant, get a repair crew on that computer.
让麦考伊到传送室去
Get McCoy down to the Transporter Room.
史波克，你跟我来，史考特，你也是
Spock, you come with me. Scotty, you too.
麦考伊医生，请到传送室
Dr. McCoy to the Transporter Room.
机械维修组C5…
Maintenance crew C5.
已经获取了它的坐标，已锁定目标
They've got the coordinates, it's locked in.
- 通电 - 通电中
- Energize. - Energizing.
- 史波克先生，探测器有发现吗？ - 没有，舰长
- Sensor readings, Mr. Spock? - Negative, captain.
它有一个保护性的屏障，我不能穿透
It has a protective screen. I cannot get through.
那我们现在要怎么做，上去敲门吗？
What do we do now, go up and knock?
请说明你的起源地
Relate your point of origin.
我们来自星际联邦
We are from the United Federation of Planets.
回答不充分
Insufficient response.
所有事物都有自己的起源地
All things have a point of origin.
我要扫描你们的星图
I will scan your star charts.
嗯，如果我们通过全貌图向它展示我们的星系
Well, if we show it a close-up view of our system,
在没有任何参照物的情况下
if it has no point of reference
它了解的不会比现在多
it won't know any more than it does now.
你说的有道理
A reasonable course.
如果你能够离开你的星舰
If you care to leave your ship,
我们会为你提供必需的维生系统
we'll provide the necessary life-support systems.
不合逻辑的推论
Non sequitur.
你的结论和事实不一致
Your facts are uncoordinated.
吉姆，我不认为它里面有生物
Jim, I don't think anybody's in there.
我不包含寄生生物，我就是诺曼
I contain no parasitical beings. I am Nomad.
- 我的意见是，它是台机器 - 确实是
- In my opinion, that's a machine. - Indeed.
它的反应就像是一台极其精密的电脑
It is reacting much like a highly sophisticated computer.
我是诺曼，什么是“意见”？
I am Nomad. What is "opinion"?
一个意见是一种信念、一个观点、一项判断
An opinion is a belief, a view, a judgement.
你的回答不充分
Insufficient response.
你能量的来源是什么？
What's your source of power?
我的能量来源已改变，不再是最初那样
It has changed since the point of origin.
大部分改变都是从“另一个”那里获取的
There was much taken from the Other.
我获得了永恒的生命，我是诺曼
I am perpetual now. I am Nomad.
在21世纪初，是不是发射过一个叫做诺曼的探测器？
Wasn't there a probe called Nomad launched in the early 2000s?
是的，据报告是毁坏了
Yes, it was reported destroyed.
也没再发射这类探测器了
There were no more in the series.
但如果它就是那个探测器…
But if this is that probe...
我要扫描你们的星图
I will scan your star charts.
我去拿给你
I will bring them.
在你的星舰里
I have the capability of movement
我能自由的移动
within your ship.
请这边走
This way.
史考特，将曲速引擎满功率运行
Now, Scotty, get our warp power up to full capacity.
- 是，长官 - 史波克，老骨头
- Aye, sir. - Spock, Bones,
和我们一起来
come with us.
- 是14A星图吗，长官？ - 是的
- Chart 14A, sir? - 14A.
- 诺曼，你能识别这个吗？ - 是的
- Nomad, can you scan that? - Yes.
这就是我们的起源地，一颗名叫索尔的行星
This is our point of origin, the star we know as Sol.
你是来自第三颗行星吗？
You are from the third planet?
- 是的 - 那颗
- Yes. - A planet
有一个巨大天然卫星的行星？
with one large natural satellite?
是的
Yes.
那颗行星是不是叫地球？
The planet is called Earth?
是的
Yes.
你是我的创造者，寇克
You are the Creator, the Kirk.
那对你的星舰就不需要进行清洗操作了
The sterilization procedure against your ship was unnecessary.
什么清洗操作？
What sterilization procedure?
你是寇克，我的创造者
You are the Kirk, the Creator.
你规定了我的职责
You programmed my function.
嗯，我不是寇克，告诉我你的职责是什么
Well, I'm not the Kirk. Tell me what your function is.
创造者，这是你的一个单元吗？
This is one of your units, Creator?
是的，他是
Yes, he is.
他的行为很不理性
It functions irrationally.
有时候吧
Sometimes.
但是无论如何告诉他你的职责
But tell him your function nevertheless.
我的职责是探测生物性的缺陷
My function is to probe for biological infestations,
摧毁不完美的生物体
to destroy that which is not perfect.
我是诺曼
I am Nomad.
探测生物性缺陷？
Biological infestation?
从没有过那样的探测器
There was never any probe sent out for that.
电脑里的历史记录能回答那个问题
The history computer can answer that question.
给我一点时间查一下
I'll have the readout in a moment.
你有没有摧毁玛鲁里安星系？
Did you destroy the Malurian system?
创造者寇克，我没有摧毁星系
Not the system, Creator Kirk,
我只摧毁了不稳定的生物性缺陷
only the unstable biological infestation.
- 那是我的职责 - 不稳定的缺陷？
- It is my function. - Unstable infestation?
你是指4颗行星上的居民？到底是怎样的职责…？
The population of four planets? What kind of function..?
医生
Doctor.
你为什么叫我创造者？
Why do you call me the Creator?
是我用词不正确吗？
Is the usage incorrect?
- 嗯，我… - 诺曼，用词是正确的
- Well, l... - The usage is correct, Nomad.
创造者只是在测试你的记忆库
The Creator was simply testing your memory banks.
在那次事故中我的记忆库确实遭受了损坏
There was much damage in the accident.
辛格先生
Mr. Singh.
过来一下
Come here a moment.
- 这个单元会为你服务的 - 长官？
- This unit will see to your needs. - Sir?
我一会就回来，先生们，跟我来
I'll be back in a moment. Gentlemen, come with me.
你有所发现，是什么？
You're onto something. What?
我搜集了所有能找到的关于诺曼探测器的信息
I've correlated all the available information on the Nomad probe
我确信它就是那个探测器
and I am convinced that this object is indeed that probe.
真荒谬，那时候地球上的科技
Ridiculous. Earth science
还不能建造能运行这么长时间的探测器
couldn't begin to build anything with those capabilities that long ago.
- 是的 - 诺曼被摧毁了
- True. - Nomad was destroyed.
应该是一颗流星撞击了它
Presumed destroyed by a meteor collision.
我猜想它遭受了很严重的损坏 但是不知怎的最终修复了自己
I submit that it was badly damaged and somehow managed to repair itself.
我在学校听过几次关于诺曼探测器的报道
I heard some lectures at the Academy on the Nomad probe.
它的任务基本上是和平的
Its mission was essentially peaceful.
我打扰到你了吗？
Did I disturb you?
你需要点什么吗？
Did you wish anything?
舰桥呼叫辅助控制室
Bridge to Auxiliary Control Room.
- 请回复 - 我是上尉辛格
- Check in, please. - Lieutenant Singh here.
所有系统正常，除了曲速动力指示器
All systems are normal, except warp-power indicators.
史考特先生的工程师们正在处理
Mr. Scott's engineers are working on them now.
当指示器正常工作后记得给他报告
Report to him when your indicators are registering properly.
还有什么其他情况吗？
Anything else?
- 等一会，上尉 - 好的
- One moment, lieutenant. - Holding.
我的心在哪里
Where my heart is
在…
Where...
在某个地方
Somewhere
越过了群星
Beyond the stars
越过了心大星
Beyond Antares
这就是诺曼的创造者
This is the creator of Nomad.
或许是当时最杰出的科学家了，尽管他很古怪
Perhaps the most brilliant, though erratic, scientist of his time.
他的梦想是建造一个完美的
His dream was to build a perfect thinking machine,
能独立进行逻辑思考的机器，你能回想起他的名字吗？
capable of independent logic. Do you recall his name?
当然了，杰克逊·罗伊寇克
Of course. Jackson Roykirk.
杰克逊·罗伊寇克，舰长詹姆士·寇克
Jackson Roykirk, Captain James Kirk.
是的，名字相近
Yes, similar.
舰长，我认为诺曼认为你就是罗伊寇克
Captain, I believe that Nomad thinks you are Roykirk.
这也可能是它停止攻击的原因
That may well be why the attack was broken off.
它对你的名字有反应，也承认了它的记忆库曾经受损
It responded to your name, as well as its damaged memory banks permitted.
史波克，我们对诺曼了解多少？
What do we have on Nomad itself, Spock?
- 嗯，并不完全一样 - 医生，基本上一样
- Well, that's not the same. - Essentially it is, doctor.
我认为除了流星撞击，还发生了其他事
I believe that more happened to it than just damage in the meteor collision.
它提到了“另一个”
It mentioned "the Other."
它还没有回答“另一个”是什么？
The unanswered question is, the Other what?
诺曼是建造过的最好的思考机器
Nomad was a thinking machine, the best to be engineered.
- 它是个设计原型 - 它的职责很明显已经改变了
- It was a prototype. - Its purpose was certainly altered.
它探测并摧毁生物性缺陷的职责
His directive to seek out and destroy biological infestations
是不可能事先被制定的
could not have been programmed into it.
据我所知，是的，它应该是作为第一颗星际探测器
As I recall, it wasn't. It was supposed to be the first interstellar probe
去搜寻新的生命形式
to seek out new life forms.
正是如此，医生
Precisely, doctor.
然而它的程序不知怎的改变了
And somehow that programming has been changed.
现在看起来诺曼正在搜寻完美的生命形式
It would seem that Nomad is now seeking out perfect life forms.
根据它无情的逻辑衡量完美
Perfection being measured by its own relentless logic.
如果你说的都是真的，那我们带了一个不定时炸弹到船上
If what you say is true, then we've taken aboard our vessel
它迟早会毁灭我们的
a device which, sooner or later, must destroy us.
保卫
Security.
- 我是上尉卡莱尔 - 我是舰长
- Lieutenant Carlisle here. - This is the captain.
我们带到船上的探测器正在辅助控制室
The mechanism we brought aboard is in the Auxiliary Control Room.
五分钟内带一队保卫和我在那里会合
Have a security team meet me there in five minutes.
- 是的，长官 - 知道了，舰长
- Aye, sir. - Acknowledge. Captain,
辛格先生报告诺曼不在辅助控制室了
Mr. Singh reports that Nomad is no longer in the Auxiliary Control Room.
保卫，取消刚才的命令
Security, cancel that order.
组织全面搜寻那颗探测器
Implement a search for the mechanism.
所有单元，发现探测器就向我报告
All decks, report to me here.
我的心在哪里
Where my heart is
在…
Where
散发香气的月亮花…
The scented lunar flower...
- 舰桥呼叫舰长 - 我是舰长
- Bridge to captain. - Captain here.
那个机器怪物到控制室来了
That mechanical beastie is up here.
史考特，我就来了
On my way, Scotty.
明天
Tomorrow
在这条道路上的一个车站
A stop along the way
那就是我心爱的地方…
There's where my love...
- 那是什么意思？ - 什么？
- What is the meaning? - What?
那是什么类型的交流？
What form of communication?
我不清楚它…
I don't know what it...
哦，你说的是唱歌，我刚在唱歌
Oh, my singing. I was singing.
唱歌是为了什么？
For what purpose is singing?
我不知道，我…我喜欢唱歌
I don't know. L... I like to sing.
我喜欢音乐
I felt like music.
什么是音乐？
What is music?
努力的想音乐
Think about music.
上尉！
Lieutenant!
- 远离那个探测器！ - 史考特
- Keep away from that thing. - Scotty!
老骨头
Bones.
吉姆，他死了
He's dead, Jim.
你为什么杀了他？
Why did you kill him?
那个单元碰到了我的屏障
The unit touched my screens.
那个…
That...
…单元是我的首席工程师
...unit was my chief engineer.
上尉
Lieutenant.
上尉，你还好吗？
Lieutenant, are you all right?
医务室
Sickbay.
你对她做了什么？
What'd you do to her?
那个单元是不完美的
That unit is defective.
她的思维很混乱
Its thinking is chaotic.
吸收她的思想让我也不稳定了
Absorbing it unsettled me.
那个单元是个女人
That unit is a woman.
一大堆矛盾混乱的冲动
A mass of conflicting impulses.
把史考特抬到下面去
Get Scott down below.
创造者，你想要修复史考特单元吗？
Will the Creator effect repairs on the unit Scott?
- 他死了 - 回答不充分
- He's dead. - Insufficient response.
他的…
His...
…生物功能被终止了
...biological functions have ceased.
创造者，你希望我修复那个单元吗？
Does the Creator wish me to repair the unit?
吉姆，我已经无能为力了
There's nothing I can do, Jim.
如果有可能，就尽快救他
If there's a chance, it'll have to be soon.
好的，诺曼，修复那个单元
All right, Nomad, repair the unit.
我需要关于构造的记录
I require tapes on the structure.
嗯，他需要关于一般解剖学的记录
Well, it'll need tapes on general anatomy,
中枢神经系统
the central nervous system,
然后是关于大脑生理结构的记录
and then one on the physiological structure of the brain.
我们最好把所有神经学的资料都给它
We'd better give it all the neurological studies we have,
还有史考特的超脑电图的记录
as well as tracings of Scotty's hyper-encephalogram.
诺曼
Nomad.
我已经安排用电脑
I have arranged the tapes for flash feed
最快的处理速度传送这些记录了
at the top speed of the computer.
请不要用超过机器处理能力的速度读取信息
Please do not draw the information faster than the machine's capacity.
开始吧
Proceed.
创造者，史考特单元是一个基本构造体
Creator, the unit Scott is a primitive structure.
没有内置足够的保障系统
Insufficient safeguards built in.
很多原因都会导致他崩溃
Breakdown can occur from many causes.
自我维护系统可靠性也很低
Self-maintenance systems of low reliability.
我的构造也是这样的，诺曼，修复它吧
It serves me as it is, Nomad. Repair it.
史考特单元现在在哪呢？
Where is the unit Scott now?
- 尸体在医务室 - 带我去医务室
- The body is in Sickbay. - Show me Sickbay.
麦考伊医生会带你去的
Dr. McCoy will show you.
护卫
Security.
我要两个全副武装的护卫24小时监视着诺曼
I want a 24-hour, two-man armed surveillance on Nomad.
把他们带到医务室
Pick him up in Sickbay.
医生，没有反应
No reaction, doctor.
我不用看也知道
I could have told you that without looking.
你们都盯着我看干什么？
What are the lot of you staring at me for?
- 真难以置信 - 太奇妙了
- It's unbelievable. - Fascinating.
- 我怎么到了这里？我怎么…？ - 没事了
- How did I get here? How did l..? - It's all right.
那个探测器要伤害乌乎拉上尉
That thing did something to Lieutenant Uhura.
有人在照看她，她没事了
She's being taken care of, it's all right.
放轻松躺下，史考特我们要给你检查
Just take it easy and lie down, Scotty. We just wanna check you out.
史考特单元被修复了
The unit Scott is repaired.
如果你给我的信息是准确的，他将正常运作
It will function correctly if your information to me was correct.
如果你不介意，我还是想检查下
I'd like to check it out, if you don't mind.
他不只是一个你拼凑起来的生物体
A man is not just a biological unit that you can patch together.
它对我做了什么？
What did it do to me?
麦考伊医生会跟你解释的
Dr. McCoy will explain it to you.
嗯，医生？
Well, doctor?
护士，我想要他做好全身检查的准备
Nurse, I want him prepared for a full physical examination.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
诺曼，到这里来
Nomad, come here.
修复那个单元
Repair that unit.
不可能
Not possible.
你都救活了史考特，他受得伤要严重的多
You restored Scott. He had much more extensive damage.
史考特单元需要简单的构造性修复
The unit Scott required simple structural repair.
这名单元的知识库都被清空了
The knowledge banks of this unit have been wiped clean.
舰长
Captain,
如果它说的是真的
if that is correct
没有大脑损伤，只是知识被清空
if there has been no brain damage, only knowledge erased,
那她可以重新学习
she could be reeducated.
- 老骨头 - 是，我立即去准备
- Bones. - Yes, I'll get on it right away.
尽管你修复了史考特，但你这个机器怪物…
And in spite of the way you repaired Scotty, you metal, ticking...
创造者你是不是想让诺曼在其他地方等待？
Does the Creator wish Nomad to wait elsewhere?
是的，诺曼
Yes. Nomad,
你跟着这些单元
you will go with these units.
他们会带你到等待区域的
They will take you to a waiting area.
把它带到舰上看管最严密的房间
Take it to the top security cell in the brig.
医生
Doctor.
我打断你
I interrupted you
是因为诺曼或许不会理解你的愤怒
because Nomad would not have understood your anger.
它有高超的技术技能
It has great technical skill
但是它对情绪的反应是很难预测的
but its reaction to emotion is unpredictable.
它几乎可以算是一个生命了
It almost qualifies as a life form.
你在开玩笑
That's a laugh.
舰长，对它的研究会很有用途
A study of it would be of great use, captain.
史波克，它是个杀人犯
It's a killer, Spock.
我要先保证它不会对人造成伤害
I intend to render it harmless.
带上你的设备去舰桥
Get down to the brig with your equipment.
对那个探测器作一次分析
Run an analysis on the mechanism.
我想知道为什么那个探测器会伤害人类
I wanna know what makes that thing tick.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
发生了什么事？
What's the problem?
舰长，它几乎和人类一样倔强
An almost human stubbornness, captain.
我无法说服诺曼
I have been unable to convince Nomad
放下它的屏障让我做检查
to lower its screens for analysis.
它如果不配合，我什么也做不了
Without its cooperation, I can do nothing.
诺曼
Nomad,
你要允许史波克先生
you will allow Mr. Spock
探测你的记忆库和其他构造
to probe your memory banks and structure.
创造者，史波克先生也是你的生化单元吗？
Mr. Spock is also one of your biological units, Creator?
是的
Yes.
这个单元不一样，他的思维很有条理
This unit is different. It is well-ordered.
诺曼，执行我的指令
Follow your instructions, Nomad.
- 我的屏障放下了 - 谢谢
- My screens are down. - Thank you.
你可以开始了
You may proceed.
- “看那条狗” - 正确
- "See the dog." - That's right.
“看那条狗…”
"See the dog..."
快，说出来
Now, sound it out.
- “奔跑” - 就是这样，乌乎拉，你表现得很好
- "Run." - That's it, Uhura. That's very good.
现在，试试下一句
Now, try the next one.
“那条狗有一个…”
"The dog has a..."
“那条狗…”
"The dog h..."
不要用斯瓦西里语，乌乎拉，用英语
Not Swahili, Uhura. In English.
那条狗有一个球，明白了吗？
The dog has a ball. See?
- 球 - 球
- Ball. - Ball.
现在，你来说吧
Now, you go ahead.
- “那条狗有一个球” - 这就对了
- "The dog has a ball." - That's right.
这就对了，乌乎拉
That's right, Uhura.
你再试试另外一句，我一会就回来
Here, you try another one. I'll be right back.
好的，克莉丝汀
All right, Christine.
她表现的怎么样？
How's she doing?
嗯，她是个一流的阅读者
Well, she's on the first-grade reader.
她正在努力学习
She's learning.
看起来她对数学很有天赋
Seems to have an aptitude for mathematics.
医生，你认为我们能够对她进行再教育吗？
Do you think we can reeducate her, doctor?
嗯，我检查过她没有大脑损伤
Well, she checks out with no brain damage.
我们的图书馆里有所有的教育资料
We've got all the educational tapes in our library.
现在就看我们的了
Now it's up to us.
“那个球是…
"The ball is...
“蓝色的”
...bluey."
蓝色的？
Bluey?
舰长，这样还不够
It is not sufficient, captain.
我得到了一些关于那次事故和“另一个”的信息
I get certain references to the accident, the Other,
但是都不详尽，还有一些地方是我检查不到的
but nothing clear. There are areas I simply cannot scan.
史波克，我们一定要知道事情的真相
We've got to know about it, Spock.
什么使得它那么执着于追求完美
What makes it operate, its compulsion for perfection.
我建议使用瓦肯人的心灵探测
Captain, I suggest the Vulcan mind probe.
你要直接和那个探测器进行精神交流？
Get into direct mental contact with that thing?
这可能是唯一的方法了
It seems the only way.
你也见到它对乌乎拉做了什么
You saw what it did to Uhura.
这样做是有风险
There is a risk.
但是我有了部分的假设 我必须检验一下
But I have formed a partial hypothesis. I must check it out.
诺曼
Nomad,
史波克单元将会接触你
the unit Spock will touch you.
那不是攻击
It is not an attack.
那是一种交流的方式，你要允许他接触你
It is a form of communication. You will permit it.
创造者，我会允许的
I will permit it, Creator.
我是诺曼
I am Nomad.
我正在执行我的任务
I am performing my function.
无尽的虚空
Deep emptiness.
它靠近
It approaches.
碰撞，损坏，黑暗
Collision, damage, blackness.
我是“另一个”
I am the Other.
我是“谭如”
I am Tan Ru.
谭如
Tan Ru.
诺曼
Nomad.
谭如
Tan Ru.
错误，缺陷
Error. Flaw.
不完美的事物
Imperfection.
必须被清洗
Must sterilize.
重生
Rebirth.
我们完整了
We are complete.
更强大的力量
Much power.
创造者指导我们
The Creator instructs.
搜寻
Search out.
识别
Identify.
清洗不完美的事物
Sterilize imperfections.
我们是诺曼
We are Nomad.
我们完整了
We are complete.
我们被指引着
We are instructed.
我们的目标明确
Our purpose is clear.
清洗不完美的事物
Sterilize imperfections.
诺曼，清洗
Nomad sterilize.
- 清洗，诺曼，清洗 - 史波克！
- Sterilize. Nomad. Sterilize. - Spock!
- 诺曼，清洗，诺曼 - 史波克！诺曼！
- Nomad. Sterilize. Nomad. - Spock! Nomad!
你还没有切断和史波克的联系，快停止
You're in contact with the unit Spock. Stop.
- 清洗 - 快停止！
- Sterilize. - Stop!
确认命令
Acknowledged.
- 史波克 - 真令人惊讶
- Spock. - Amazing.
- 史波克 - 舰长，太奇妙了
- Spock. - Fascinating, captain.
它拥有极为丰富的知识
The knowledge, the depth.
“我们是诺曼”，是什么意思？
What does it mean, "We are Nomad"?
它…
It was...
它在太空深处被损坏了
It was damaged in deep space.
毫无疑问是由于流星的撞击
Undoubtedly the meteor collision.
它的记忆库损坏了，或者大部分记忆库
Its memory banks were destroyed, or most of them.
它漫无目的的漂浮着，然后它遇到了“另一个”
It wandered without purpose. And then it met the Other.
“另一个”是一颗强大的外星人探测器
The Other was an alien probe of great power.
不知怎么地他们融合了
Somehow they merged.
互相修复，变成了一个整体
Repaired each other, became one.
它不再是诺曼
Then it isn't Nomad.
不是我们从地球发射的诺曼
Not the Nomad we launched from Earth.
它从“另一个”获取了新的职责，替代了原来的职责
It took from the Other a new directive to replace its own.
“另一个”起初被用来检测和消毒
The Other was originally programmed to secure and sterilize
其他行星上的土壤
soil samples from other planets.
或许是为了殖民做准备
Probably as a prelude to colonization.
这是一出“狸猫换太子”的戏码
A changeling.
请原谅
I beg your pardon.
史波克先生，这是一则古老的地球传说
An ancient Earth legend, Mr. Spock.
“狸猫换太子”是指被偷换后留下的侏儒婴孩
A changeling was a fairy child that was left in place of a human baby.
被替换的婴孩因此有了人类婴孩的身份
The changeling assumed the identity of the human child.
那么它现在的职责就是清洗
So it is to sterilize.
而清洗，意味着杀戮
And for sterilize, read kill.
而它有能力并且有理由去杀戮
And it has the power and the sophistication to do it.
是的，它很强大
Yes, it's powerful
而且有足够理由 但是它也不是不会犯错误
and sophisticated, but it's not infallible.
这下大家高兴了
It's space happy.
它认为我是它的创造者
It thinks I'm its mother.
而这是唯一使我们活到现在的原因
And that is the only thing that has saved us until now.
是的
Yes.
快通知舰长
Notify the captain.
你到这里干什么？
What are you doing here?
大家注意你们面前的仪器
Watch your panels, everyone.
注意观察核反应堆状态
Watch that polymass.
罗杰，帮他观察反应堆
Roger, help with the interfactor.
别碰它
Leave that alone.
这个基础的物质-反物质推进系统就是主动力来源吗？
This primitive matter-antimatter propulsion system is the main drive?
是的
Aye.
反物质的投放量让这个系统效率很低
Inefficiency exists in the antimatter input valve.
我来修复它
I will effect repair.
你在干什么？
How are you doing that?
能量利用系统也是最低效的
The energy-release controls are also most inefficient.
我来修复它
I shall effect repair.
史考特先生，曲速8级，并且还在增长
Warp 8, Mr. Scott, and increasing.
增大阻尼器
Lower your dampers.
曲速9级
Warp 9.
把所有的电路都切断
Cut your circuits, all of them.
史考特先生，曲速10级
Warp 10, Mr. Scott.
不可能，我们的星舰不可能飞那么快
Impossible. It can't go that fast.
史考特先生，它就是停不下来，现在曲速11级
She just won't stop, Mr. Scott. Warp 11.
诺曼，停下来
Nomad, stop what you're doing.
史考特
Scotty.
创造者，我这么做有问题吗？
Is there a problem, Creator?
我已经把引擎的效率提高了57%
I have increased engine efficiency 57 percent.
你这么做会毁了这艘星舰的
You will destroy my ship.
它的结构承受不了这么多能量产生的压力
Its structure cannot stand the stress of that much power.
- 关闭修复操作 - 确认命令
- Turn off your repair operation. - Acknowledged.
创造者，引擎已经恢复原来状态了
It is reversed as ordered, Creator.
史考特先生，告诉苏鲁把速度设定并保持在曲速2级
Mr. Scott, give Sulu warp 2 and keep her there.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
舰长
Captain.
我检查过舰桥
I've examined the brig.
保卫室的力场门被破坏了
The force-field door on the security cell is damaged.
而且护卫失踪了，我认为他们死了
And the guards have vanished. I must assume they are dead.
- 你杀死了我的两个… - 创造者
- You killed two of my... - Creator,
你的生物体单元都很低效
your biological units are inefficient.
诺曼，是时候该告诉你你到底是什么了
Nomad, it's about time I told you who and what you are.
我是一个生物体而我创造了你
I'm a biological unit and I created you.
不合逻辑的推论，生物体是处于先天劣势的
Non sequitur. Biological units are inherently inferior.
这是自相矛盾的
This is an inconsistency.
诺曼，外面有两个人在等着你
Nomad, there are two men waiting outside.
你不能伤害他们，他们会护送你
You will not harm them. They will escort you back
回到等候区
to the waiting area.
你要呆在那里，什么也不要做
You will stay there. You will do nothing.
我的职责是探测生物性缺陷
I am programmed to investigate.
我给了你新的任务，你要执行它
I have given you new programming, and you will implement it.
在我返回我的发射点之前
There is much to be considered
有太多的事情需要考虑
before I return to launch point.
我需要重新评估
I must reevaluate.
重新评估？
Reevaluate?
我觉得它是要重新评估它的创造者
I suspect it is about to reevaluate its creator.
向诺曼承认是一个生物体
It may have been unwise to admit to Nomad
或许不是个明智的决定
that you are a biological unit.
在诺曼的眼里，你现在一定不完美了
In Nomad's eyes, you must now undoubtedly appear imperfect.
那是个愚蠢的错误
It was a foolish mistake.
更严重的是
Even worse,
诺曼刚提到了它的发射地点，地球
Nomad just now made a reference to its launch point, Earth.
史波克，你认为那可能吗？
Spock, do you think it's possible
在它刚才入侵电脑的时候获得了地球的坐标？
that it got a fix on Earth when it tapped the computers earlier?
我相信，以诺曼的能力，这并不是什么难事
I do not believe there is much beyond Nomad's capabilities.
我们指给了它回家的路
Then we've shown it the way home.
当它回到地球的时候…
And when it gets there...
它会发现地球上充斥着不完美的生物体
It will find the Earth infested with imperfect biological units.
而它则会执行它最重要的使命：
And it will carry out its prime directive:
清洗
Sterilize.
舰长日志，星历3541.9
Captain's log, stardate 3541.9.
诺曼出现在我的星舰上变得像是噩梦一样
The presence of Nomad aboard my ship has become nightmarish.
现在它明显表示要返回地球
Now it apparently means to return to Earth.
一旦它回到那里，它会自动毁灭所有生命
Once there, it would automatically destroy all life.
嘿，诺曼，停下来
Hey, Nomad, stop.
诺曼，你要走这边
Nomad, this way.
寇克舰长请到医务室，这里有紧急情况
Captain Kirk to Sickbay. Emergency.
手动控制
Manual controls.
没有反应
No response.
诺曼，诺曼
Nomad. Nomad.
停下来
Stop.
诺曼，停下来！
Nomad, stop!
诺曼
Nomad.
她还好吗？
Is she all right?
是的
I think so.
看起来她好像受了惊吓
It looks like some kind of shock.
发生了什么事？
What happened?
诺曼检查了人事档案和病历
Nomad examined the personnel files and the medical history.
她试图制止它
She tried to stop him.
- 谁的病历？ - 你的
- Whose history? - Yours.
既然它特地查看了你的病历
Since it specifically examined your history,
我认为它已经完成了重新评估
I suggest it has completed its reevaluation.
并且发现它的创造者
And found that its creator
和其他生物体一样不完美
is as imperfect as all the other biological units.
舰桥呼叫舰长
Bridge to captain.
- 我是寇克 - 整艘船的生命维持系统
- Kirk here. - Life-support systems are out
都不再运转
all over the ship.
手动操作也被屏蔽，屏蔽来源：轮机层
Manual override has been blocked. Source: Engineering.
- 是诺曼 - 肯定是它
- Nomad. - Undoubtedly.
现在生命维持系统关闭了
With the systems out,
我们只还有一些空气和热量…
we'll only have enough air and heat...
去找史考特，让他带一些反重力装备到轮机层见我
Get Scotty, some antigravs and meet me in Engineering.
诺曼
Nomad,
快停下来
stop what you're doing
修复生命维持系统
and effect repairs on the life-support systems.
停下来
Stop.
你应该听从创造者的命令
You're programmed to obey the orders of your creator.
我的职责是摧毁那些不完美的生命形式
I am programmed to destroy those life forms which are imperfect.
我做的改造会摧毁那些不完美的生命
These alterations will do so without destroying
而不会损坏我们所在的星舰
the vessel which surrounds them.
这艘星舰虽然也不完美，但是它可以被改造
It too is imperfect, but can be adjusted.
诺曼
Nomad.
我承认生物体不完美
I admit that biological units are imperfect,
但是你是被一个生物体创造的
but a biological unit created you.
我是完美的，我是诺曼
I am perfect. I am Nomad.
不，你不是诺曼，你是一个外星探测器
No, you're not Nomad. You're an alien machine.
你的源代码已经改变了
Your programming tapes have been altered.
你的说法不正确
You are in error.
你是个生物体，你不是完美的
You are a biological unit. You are imperfect.
- 但我是你的创造者 - 你是创造者
- But I am your creator. - You are the Creator.
- 我创造了你 - 你是创造者
- I created you. - You are the Creator.
但我承认我不完美
But I admit I am imperfect.
我是怎么创造了你这么一个完美的机械呢？
How could I have created such a perfect thing as you?
答案未知，我需要分析
Answer unknown. I shall analyse.
分析完成，缺乏充足数据回答问题
Analysis complete. Insufficient data to resolve problem.
但是我的职责还在
But my programming is whole. My purpose remains.
我是诺曼，我是完美的
I am Nomad. I am perfect.
那些不完美的事物都要被清洗
That which is imperfect must be sterilized.
那你将继续摧毁
Then you will continue to destroy
那些思考不完美，生活不完美
that which thinks and lives
甚至本身就不完美的生命？
and is imperfect?
我将继续执行我的使命
I shall continue.
我将返回我的发射地点地球
I shall return to launch point Earth.
我将继续清洗
I shall sterilize.
即使有错误，你一定要清洗
You must sterilize in case of error.
错误和我的主要职责不一致
Error is inconsistent with my prime function.
清洗是绝对正确的
Sterilization is correction.
所有有错误的事物都要被清洗？
Everything that is in error must be sterilized?
没有例外
There are no exceptions.
诺曼
Nomad,
在创造你时，我犯了一个错误
I made an error in creating you.
对完美事物的创造是没有错误的
The creation of perfection is no error.
我没有创造出完美的事物，我犯错了
I did not create perfection, I created error.
你的数据是错误的，我是诺曼，我是完美的
Your data is faulty. I am Nomad. I am perfect.
我是寇克，我是你的创造者吗？
I am the Kirk, the Creator?
你是我的创造者
You are the Creator.
你搞错了！
You're wrong!
你的创造者是杰克逊·罗伊寇克，他已经死了
Jackson Roykirk, your creator, is dead.
你把我错当做他了
You have mistaken me for him.
你并不完美，你没有发现你犯的错误
You are in error. You did not discover your mistake.
你犯了两个错误
You have made two errors.
你是有缺陷的，不完美的
You are flawed and imperfect.
你有缺陷，却没有被清洗，你犯了三个错误
And you have not corrected by sterilization. You've made three errors.
错误！错误！错误！
Error! Error! Error!
检查
Examine.
你是有缺陷的，不完美的
You are flawed and imperfect.
快执行你的职责吧
Execute your prime function.
我需要分析错误
I shall analyse error.
分析错误
Analyse error.
就是现在，把那些反重力装备放到他身上
Now. Get those antigravs on it.
检查错误，错误
Examine error. Error.
趁它还在思考赶紧解决它
Get rid of it while it's thinking.
舰长，你的逻辑是无可挑剔的
Your logic was impeccable, captain
我们现在很危险
We are in grave danger.
- 史考特，带它去传送室 - 分析错误
- Scotty, Transporter Room. - Analyse error.
- 错误 - 史考特
- Error. - Scotty,
把传送目的地设置到深空210，标记12
set the controls for deep space, 210, mark 12.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
错误的
Faulty.
- 可以了吗，长官？ - 错误的
- Ready, sir? - Faulty.
诺曼，你不完美
Nomad, you are imperfect.
错误
Error.
- 错误 - 执行你的职责吧
- Error. - Exercise your prime function.
错误的，错误的事物
Faulty. Faulty.
必须要清洗
Must sterilise.
清洗
Sterilise.
- 就是现在 - 启动传送
- Now. - Energizing.
舰长，恭喜你，你的逻辑真的无可挑剔
My congratulations, captain. A dazzling display of logic.
你觉得我一直思维不清晰，是不是？
Didn't think I had it in me, did you?
是的，长官
No, sir.
我觉得你可能想知道
Thought you might like to know,
乌乎拉的知识现在恢复到大学水平了
Uhura is back to college level.
她在一周内就可以回到岗位上了
We should have her back within a week.
做的好，老骨头
Good, Bones, good.
- 真令人印象深刻 - 你说什么？
- Remarkable. - What?
舰长，诺曼的毁灭对我们来说是巨大的损失
The destruction of Nomad was a great waste, captain.
它是个非比寻常的机器
It was a remarkable instrument.
它也能毁灭数十亿人的生命，它死得其所
Which might well have destroyed more billions of lives. It's well gone.
而且，你为了什么那么难过？
Besides, what are you feeling so badly about?
丢掉那么一个出色而有前途的孩子倒是让我很难受
It's not easy to lose a bright and promising son.
长官？
Sir?
嗯
Well,
它认为我是它的创造者、它的母亲，是不是？
it thought I was its mother, didn't it?
史波克，难道你认为我真的没有感情吗？
Do you think I'm completely without feelings, Spock?
你也见到它对史考特所做的事情
You saw what it did for Scotty.
它能成为怎样的一名医生啊
What a doctor it would have made.
我的孩子，一名医生
My son, the doctor.
多少能触动到你这里，不是吗？
Kind of gets you right there, doesn't it?
本集完
谢谢观赏
-=The Last Fantasy=-
TLF字幕组欢迎你，欢迎有志之士加入
TLF中文字幕站http://tlfsubs.eastgame.org/